David Dangerfield | Frontend Developer

Greater Minneapolis-St. Paul Area



linkedin.com/in/dangerfield

Summary

- 6 years frontend development: JavaScript, Vue.js, CSS, HTML, etc.
- 14 years backend development: Java, and older languages.

I love frontend development--especially with Vue.js!

Working software is my focus. The best software designs and architectures _emerge_ through agile software development/test and frequent client feedback.

I am a fan of: frontendmasters.com, meetups/conferences/workshops, respect for UI/UX designers, keeping things simple/maintainable, short iterations, continuous delivery, etc.

Want a formal bio?

David has been developing software for over 20 years, focusing solely on front-end since 2014. His strong foundation in computer science, good real-world experience, and passion for staying current, make him a compelling addition to any org. While his current focus is front-end development, past roles have given him broad experience in back-end, test, and deployment automation.

Experience

Principal Frontend Software Engineer Consultant

NextEra Analytics

Jan 2021 - Present (1 month +)

Helping make renewable energy more efficient and affordable. Developing software to help leaders plan work in a way that maximizes value and minimizes cost.

Vue.js, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Git, Jira



Senior Frontend Developer/Consultant

David A. Dangerfield

Jan 2018 - Present (3 years 1 month +)

Providing consulting and services for frontend software projects in the Vue.js ecosystem.

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, Vuex, GraphQL, Nuxt.js, Cypress, Jest, Jira, Jenkins, Vuetify, Material Design, Git, etc.



Senior Frontend Engineer

SmugMug

Sep 2018 - Jan 2021 (2 years 5 months)

Helped develop and maintain smugmug.com: D which hosts "billions of happy photos" and boasts "millions of passionate customers".

Some hightlights include:

- Frontend Stripe integration
- Frontend code to support A/B tests for subscriber growth experiments
- Developed frontend for a Quickstart Guide to help new clients understand the site

Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript (and a popular library that starts with the letter "R"), GraphQL, Tailwind CSS, Sentry, Snowplow, Looker, Git, GitHub, Jenkins, Jira, Visual Studio Code, Slack, and a Kanban methodology with continuous integration & deployment.

Lead Frontend Developer / Architect, IBM Services

IBM Services

Jan 2018 - Aug 2018 (8 months)

Led the front-end development of a web app to view and update company financial and contractual information.

Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript (and a popular framework that starts with the letter "A"), REST, Material Design, Git, Git Town, ZenHub, Visual Studio Code, Slack.

FED@IBM Rochester Branch co-founder/co-leader

IBM Services

Dec 2017 - Aug 2018 (9 months)

Co-founded and led the front-end developer group at IBM Rochester. It aims to foster front-end developer cohesion in Rochester, MN. Meetings help people level-up on the latest in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js and UI/UX.

- attend and publicize tech talks every other week
- encourage members to volunteer to give talks
- give talks myself as needed
- encourage attendance by non-IBM community professionals

📰 Frontend (UI) Developer, Watson Health Consulting Services

IBM Services

Nov 2015 - Dec 2017 (2 years 2 months)

Developed custom cognitive web/mobile applications for clients in the healthcare industry and beyond. Focused on front-end work.

Sep '17 - Dec '17: Developed cognitive, web app to improve efficiency for the call center of a top 50 US bank. Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, Vuex, Github.

May '17 - Aug '17: Developed cognitive web app to assist IBM sales professionals. Implemented responsive design (iPhone5 to desktop) with HTML CSS and JavaScript. Used Vue.js, Vuex (i.e. Flux architecture a la Redux) Bluemix (IBM Cloud hosting), Webpack, Google Analytics, Github Enterprise

Jan '17 - Apr '17: Developed cognitive web app to assist pharmaceutical researchers in drug development. (A customization of IBM Watson for Drug Discovery). Implemented UI designs with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Used JS framework "AJS" & Visual Studio Code. Led small team of UI developers. https://www.ibm.com/us-en/marketplace/ibm-watson-for-drug-discovery

Dec '16 - Feb '17: Developed Watson cognitive business intelligence web app for business consultants. Implemented UI with HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Used "AJS" 1.5 components.

Oct '16 - Nov '16: Developed rough prototype web app for healthcare workers to visualize health issues on a map of the human body. Used D3.js, three.js (3D lib) and "A"

Apr '16 - Sept '16: Developed iPad and desktop web app to assist healthcare workers quickly digest patient history and system recommendations for diabetes treatment. Implemented responsive designs using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Used similar technologies to prior role.

Nov '15 - Feb '16: Developed mobile-first web app to engage and inform healthcare consumers and improve compliance. Implemented responsive designs using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Developed an "AJS" component generator to make boilerplate easy. Used: "AJS" 1.5 components, Karma + Jasmine unit testing, Protractor e2e test, ES6, Babel, Gulp, JSPM, Sublime Text

Senior Web Application Developer

Preventice Solutions

Aug 2013 - Oct 2015 (2 years 3 months)

May 2014 - Oct. 2015: UI development on multitenant cloud-based web application for the healthcare industry. Implemented ability to login as multi-role user then change role without re-login. Javascript, JQuery, JQueryUI, claims-based authorization (SAML), and [redacted MS technologies]

Jan. 2014 - Apr. 2014: Platform development in support of BodyGuardian remote patient monitoring system. Built Notification Service that ran as a Windows service and consumed messages on ActiveMQ. Built web services to return data for user groups and care teams. RESTful services, ActiveMQ, MacOS, Agile methods, and [redacted MS technologies]

Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2013: Backend Java development on custom web applications for clients in the healthcare industry. Built web services to CRUD patient healthcare protocols (Java, Tomcat). Automated integration test suite (JUnit). Researched and added code coverage analysis to build (EclEmma - JaCoCo).

Mentored new team members.

Education



Purdue University

Master of Science - MS, Computer Science 2000 - 2002



Brigham Young University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science

Licenses & Certifications



IBM Design Thinking Practitioner - IBM Services